trademic.com 2015-05-14

# Privacy Policy

At trademic.com, your privacy is a top priority. Please read our privacy policy details.

Overview

Our Internet Store allows you to buy products and gift cards, enter contests, receive special discounts, apply for credit, fill out surveys, and receive newsletters, e-mails or other promotional information from us. We use the information that we collect about you to fulfill your product and service purchases and to create a more personalized online experience. This is just a brief overview, so please read on for more details about our Privacy Policy. This Policy may change from time to time, so please check back periodically. Except as limited below, we reserve the right to use or disclose your personally identifiable information for business reasons in whatever manner desired. All information collected from you will be shared with trademic.com and its affiliate companies.

Except as otherwise discussed in this Privacy Policy, this document only addresses the use and disclosure of information we collect from you online. We encourage you to ask questions and to be very cautious before you disclose your personal information to anyone.

This Privacy Policy will explain the following regarding use of our site:

What information does trademic.com collect from you?

In order to better provide you with numerous products and services, trademic.com collects two types of information about its visitors: Personally Identifiable Information and Non-Personally Identifiable Information. Our primary goal in collecting information from you is to provide you with a smooth, efficient, and customized experience while using our site.

Personally Identifiable Information  
This refers to information that lets us know the specifics of who you are. Personal information is requested when you register and set up an account, order a product or service, register for a Gift List, enter contests or sweepstakes, fill out surveys, and send us feedback. For example, this information might include your name, billing address, shipping address, telephone number, e-mail address, credit card or other payment information, and product details. With this information, trademic.com can fill your orders and better provide you with personalized services.

Non-Personally Identifiable Information  
This refers to information that does not by itself identify a specific individual. We gather certain information about you based upon where you shop on our site in several ways. This information is compiled and analyzed on both a personal and an aggregated basis. For example, this information may include the Web site's Uniform Resource Locator ("URL") that you just came from, which URL you next go to, what browser you are using, and your Internet Protocol ("IP") address. A URL is the global address of documents and other resources on the World Wide Web. An IP address is an identifier for a computer or device on a Transmission Control Protocol/Internet Protocol ("TCP/IP") network, such as the World Wide Web. Networks like the Web use the TCP/IP protocol to route information based on the IP address of the destination. In other words, an IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the web, allowing web servers to locate and identify your computer. Computers require IP addresses in order for users to communicate on the Internet, browse and shop.

On an aggregated basis, we collect anonymous data related to the pages, products, and other content that is sampled, clicked on, and searched for. Except as otherwise limited in this Policy, we may disclose, sell, trade, or rent Non-Personally Identifiable Information to others without your consent.

Where do we collect information from you and how do we use it?

Our primary goal in collecting personal information is to provide trademic.com's visitors with a superior customized online experience. We use the customer contact information to fill orders, contact purchasers to inform them of their order status, to send promotional information, to enhance the operation of our site and administer our systems.

Demographic data also may be collected at our site from third party advertising servers, content servers, or web site analysis agents who provide us with the zip code and area code associated with a visitor's server, along with pages viewed on our site. We review the actions of the trademic.com visitors on an aggregate basis to determine customers' preferences. trademic.com also does research on our visitors' demographics, interests, and pages viewed based on the information provided to us during ordering, a promotion, from our server log files, from our web site analysis agents, or from contests, drawings or surveys. We will use this data to tailor the visitor's experience at our site, to improve our marketing and promotional efforts, to statistically analyze site use, to improve our product offerings, and to customize our site's content, layout, and services. We receive reports from third party ad servers, content servers, or website analysis agents that tell us how many ads were presented and clicked upon or what content was served or viewed.

We may also share your personally identifiable information with third parties who provide services to us, our customers and website visitors. Those third parties include authorized contractors, temporary employees and consultants and other companies working with us (collectively, "agents"). If we believe it to be appropriate, in our sole discretion, we will ask our agents not to disclose or use your personal information for purposes other than to provide services to you or trademic.com.

We gather information in the following ways:

Shopping  
We collect IP addresses for the purposes of system administration, to gather broad demographic information, to enable ads to be served on our site, and to monitor the level of activity on our site. We collect information from visitors to our site regarding the URLs they came from, domain types (i.e., .com or .org), their IP addresses, the date and time of their visit or order, the number of visits and orders, the number of visits per browsing session, the server type, the operating system and browser type used to come to the site, the country, state and telephone area code where their servers are located, the pages and page titles of our site that visitors viewed during their visit, whether the visitor's computer is enabled for Java or cookies, browser language, applications and plug-ins, and any search terms entered on our site.

Ordering  
When you order from us, we collect personally identifiable information from you. If you order one of our products or services, we will collect and maintain your name, e-mail address, billing address, shipping address, telephone number, product selections, credit card or other payment information, order number, referring URL, IP address, page you bought from and a password (if applicable). We collect this, and other information, as disclosed in this Policy, in order to fill your order, to communicate with you about your order and to send you promotional materials. Before confirming your order, you will have the opportunity to review the product order form and make changes and additions to the information it contained and these changes will be automatically kept for future use. We may require additional verifications or information before accepting any order.

Gift Certificates  
If you purchase a gift certificate from our site, you will give us the recipient's name and e-mail address if you wish to send the certificate by e-mail. The recipient information you give us will only be used to send the gift certificate and for no other purpose.

Online Surveys and Polling  
In order to improve our services to you, we ask some of our customers to voluntarily complete surveys, which may be collected by an independent third party. Individual survey answers are confidential, although Non-Personally Identifiable Information is collected and disclosed to third parties. If you do not wish to participate in a survey, simply decline to participate when asked.

Contests and Sweepstakes  
When you enter a contest or other promotion, we may ask you for contact information such as your name, address and e-mail address in order to administer the contest, to send you promotional e-mails, notify winners and make the winners' list publicly available pursuant to certain states' laws. Your consent to such promotional use and disclosure of this information is a condition of your participation. As a condition of receiving any prize, you will be required to submit an Affidavit of Eligibility, for us to ensure that you are eligible to receive the prize according to the Contest Rules.

Newsletters, Promotional E-mails and Personalized On-line Ads  
We offer free newsletters, such as our trademic.com Informational Newsletter, promotional e-mails and personalized on-line advertisements as a service to our customers. We will send you newsletters and e-mails periodically listing current specials and deals. You may "opt-out," or unsubscribe from our newsletters, emails or personalized on-line advertisements by following any unsubscribe instructions in any e-mail, newsletter or personalized on-line advertisement you receive from us, or by sending an e-mail to info@trademic.com. After doing so, if you have opted out of receiving all newsletters, all promotional emails or all personalized on-line ads, you will not receive future promotional emails, newsletters or personalized on-line advertisements (as applicable), unless you open a new account, enter a contest, or otherwise subsequently sign up to receive newsletters, emails or personalized on-line advertisements.

Contact Information and Third Party Data  
If you contact trademic.com or our customer service representatives by telephone, e-mail or letter, we may keep a record of your correspondence or comments. If you report a problem with our site, we may collect such information in a file specific to you. If you contact us through our feedback area or by calling one of our customer service representatives, we may ask for your name, e-mail address and order information in order to send you a reply. If other users or third parties send us correspondence about your activities or purchases on our site, we may keep the information in a file specific to you.

Affiliate Program  
Our Affiliate Program (Commission Junction) is administered by a third party, on a third party's Web site. Any information collected by them is not governed by this Policy.

Advertising  
We may display advertisements on our site. By knowing a little about you, trademic.com will be able to deliver more relevant advertisements and content to you in the form of targeted banners and promotions.

Web Site Use  
We also track customers' traffic patterns throughout their online session, including which pages, information and advertisements a customer views while using the site and what items they place in their basket or purchase. We use your IP address to diagnose problems with our servers, software, to administer our site and to gather demographic information. We may share aggregated statistics about pages viewed on our site, sales and other shopping information with third parties.

Cookies  
We use cookies and may allow others to use cookies in the operation of our site; to find out what cookies are and how they are used.

Action Tags/Web Beacons  
We may use and allow others to use action tags or web beacons in the operation of our site; to find out what action tags and web beacons are and how they are used.

 Who is collecting your information?

Ad Servers and Content Servers  
We may use third party ad servers or content servers to serve ads, product information, or other information both on and off our site. Those third parties may use "action tags" or web beacons throughout the site to count the number of visitors who click on a banner ad or other information and to track the number of customers who continue on to make a purchase. They may also place their own "cookie" on your computer to help those ads to run, analyze site usage and to provide you with personalized on-line advertisements. With respect to personalized on-line ad serving, our third party ad server may collect your first name and/or a product group/category (chosen by trademic.com based on your personal preferences and/or prior purchase history i.e., brooches, Murano glass, Italian charms), which are used to serve you the most relevant personalized on-line ad.

Image Servers  
We use a third party image serving company to serve the graphics that visitors see on our site more quickly. They collect a visitor's IP address and the URLs of any graphics viewed and the date and time of the visit. However, they do not collect and we do not provide them with any Personally Identifiable Information. They may also use a "cookie."

Website Analysis Agent  
We may contract with several online partners to help manage and optimize our Internet business and marketing. We use the services of marketing companies to help us measure the effectiveness of our advertising and how visitors use our site. To do this, we use Action Tags and cookies provided by the marketing companies on this site. The type of information we collect includes things such as pages, information and advertisements viewed as well as what items are placed in a shopping basket or purchased, the order number, the amount of a purchase, the product number and the quantity purchased. By supplementing our records, this information helps us learn things like what kinds of customers our site attracts, which of our products most interest our customers, and what kinds of offers our customers like to see. Although the marketing companies log the information coming from our site on our behalf, we control how that data may and may not be used. For more information, please see the section "Use of Cookies and Action Tags" below.

With whom do we share your information?

Fulfillment  
The information collected by trademic.com is used for processing orders, keeping you informed about your order status, for statistical purposes, for improving our site and its performance, to serve ads, and to notify you of products or special offers that may be of interest to you. We will disclose your Personally Identifiable Information to third parties to charge your credit card, fill your order, and deliver your order. For example, we must release your credit card information to the card-issuing bank to confirm payment; and release your address and telephone information to the delivery service to deliver products that you ordered.

Other Parties Generally  
We may provide Non-Personally Identifiable Information about our customers' sales, traffic patterns, and related site information to third parties, but these statistics do not include any Personally Identifiable Information. We may release account information when we believe that such release is reasonably necessary to enforce or apply our Terms of Use or to protect the rights, property, and safety of trademic.com, our users, or others. If customers do not pay us for products ordered, we may submit their account information to a third party collection agency. We may also share your Personally Identifiable Information with third parties who provide services to us, our customers and web site visitors. Those third parties include authorized contractors, temporary employees and consultants and other companies working with. If we believe it to be appropriate, in our sole discretion, we will ask our agents not to disclose or use your personal information for purposes other than to provide services to you or trademic.com.

Data Analysis Agents  
The information collected by or for trademic.com may be provided to an outside company for the purpose of analysis. That analysis is to help us to improve our site and product selection, and to notify you of special offers that may be of interest to you. That data analysis agent may not share any Personally Identifiable Information with others, or use it for any other purpose than to help trademic.com.

Compliance with Service of Process or Law Enforcement  
Occasionally trademic.com may be asked by law enforcement or judicial authorities to provide Personally Identifiable Information to the appropriate governmental authorities. We will disclose Personally Identifiable Information upon receipt of a court order, subpoena, or to cooperate with a law enforcement investigation, without prior notice to you. trademic.com fully cooperates with law enforcement agencies in identifying those who use our services for illegal activities. We reserve the right to report to law enforcement agencies any activities that we believe to be unlawful.

Sweepstakes and Drawings  
When you enter a sweepstakes, drawing or other promotion, we may provide entry information, including name, address, email address and age to a third-party company providing the prize or sponsoring the promotion. They may use your Personally Identifiable Information to send you marketing or promotional materials or other communications.

Sale of the Company  
trademic.com and its affiliates each reserve the right to disclose your Personally Identifiable Information in the event that any such company is sold, in whole or in part, either as an entire corporate entity or through an asset sale that includes a customer information database. This right is reserved whether or not the customer database is sold independently of any continuing operations of such company.

How can you update or correct your Personally Identifiable Information?

We believe you should have the ability to access and edit the personal information that you have provided to us. During the online ordering process you can review, change, or delete the information that you have submitted. You may change any of your personal information in your account online at any time. We encourage you to promptly update your information if it changes. You may ask to have the information on your account deleted or removed; however, because we keep track of past purchases, you cannot delete information associated with past purchases. Also, as a security measure we "back up" the data stored on our systems, and such prior information cannot be completely removed from our databases. As a result, you should not expect that all of your Personally Identifiable Information will be completely removed from our backed-up databases.

What are your choices regarding collection, use, and distribution of your information?

You may "opt-out," or unsubscribe from our newsletters, emails or personalized on-line advertisements by following any unsubscribe instructions in any e-mail, newsletter or personalized on-line advertisement you receive from us, or by sending an e-mail to info@trademic.com. After doing so, if you have opted out of receiving all newsletters, all promotional emails or all personalized on-line ads, you will not receive future promotional emails, newsletters or personalized on-line advertisements (as applicable), unless you open a new account, enter a contest, or otherwise subsequently sign up to receive newsletters, emails or personalized on-line advertisements.

Ad-servers and other Content Servers: You may also set your browser so that it will not accept "cookies" to prevent assignment from the ad server of a unique identifier; however, you may experience difficulty shopping on our site and performing other transactions if you do so.

What security precautions are in place to protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of your information?

In order to most efficiently serve you, credit card transactions and order fulfillment are handled by established third party banking, processing agents and distribution institutions. They receive the information needed to verify and authorize your credit card or other payment information and to process and ship your order.

Within trademic.com, your information is kept on password protected, limited access servers. Wherever possible and applicable, trademic.com servers reside behind a corporate firewall that maintains controls on access to the system from both our internal network and the Internet.

A special note about children's privacy

You must be at least 18 years old to have our permission to use this site. Our policy is that we do not knowingly collect, use or disclose Personally Identifiable Information about visitors under 13 years of age. If you are the parent or guardian of a child under 13 years of age and believe that they have disclosed personally identifiable information to us, please contact us at [info@trademic.com](mailto:info@trademic.com) so that we may delete the child's information.

trademic.com and third-party use of "cookies" and "action tags."

trademic.com Cookies: When you use our site we will store cookies on your computer in order to facilitate and customize your use of our site. A cookie is a small data text file, which a Web site stores on your computer's hard drive (if your Web browser permits) that can later be retrieved to identify you to trademic.com. Our cookies store randomly assigned user identification numbers, the country where you are located, and your first name to welcome you back to our site. The cookies make your use of the site easier, allow you to retrieve an earlier shopping cart, make the site run more smoothly and help us to maintain a secure site. You will be unable to shop on our site without your browser set to accept cookies.

Image Server Cookies: As part of the ad-serving process, a third party may serve graphics upon our site. In order to customize their service, they may also place a cookie upon your computer. While trademic.com does not control their use of that cookie, no Personally Identifiable or individual customers' product information is collected.

Website Analysis Agent Cookies: We may use a third party to analyze what our visitors find to be most interesting on our site. To do that, they will place a cookie on your computer with a randomly assigned unique number in order to track the pages you view on our site, along with other Non-Personally Identifiable Information.

Action Tags, Web Beacons and other Data Collection Methods: An action tag or a web-beacon (also known as a clear gif or a pixel tag) is a method used to track responses or actions by customers who view certain advertisements or other information on our site. Action tags are 1x1 pixel images embedded in a website page that are used to transparently collect information. Our ad server, content servers, affiliate program manager and website analysis agents may use action tags to count the number of times that visitors click on a particular banner ad or visit the pages of our site and to provide information about what products are viewed or purchased. Without collecting any personally identifiable information, they use that data to tell us (and other advertisers) which ads are the most effective on particular sites. Our ad server, content server, affiliate program manager and website analysis agents may use an action tag on our basket page, checkout page, and other pages, to keep anonymous track of the number of times that clicking on a banner ad or views other information on our site results in a purchase. They also collect the amount of the purchase, order confirmation number, stock keeping unit number, quantity and identity of product purchased.

You should carefully review privacy policies of any third party sites accessible from trademic.com

Other sites accessible through our web site have their own privacy policies and data collection, use and disclosure practices. Please consult each site's privacy policy. trademic.com is not responsible for the policies or practices of third parties. Please be aware that this site may contain links to other sites on the Internet that are owned and operated by third parties. The information practices of those web sites linked to trademic.com are not covered by this Privacy Policy. These other sites may send their own cookies to users, collect data, or solicit personal information. We cannot control this collection of information. You should contact these sites directly if you have any questions about their use of the information that they collect.

Contacting trademic.com about privacy questions or concerns

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this site, please contact trademic.com

Privacy Policy changes

This Privacy Policy was last changed on April 20, 2006. If trademic.com makes changes to any terms or conditions of the Privacy Policy, the changes will be posted in this document so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information and to whom we will disclose it. We may change, modify, add or remove portions of this Policy at any time, and any changes will become effective immediately upon being posted unless we tell you otherwise.
